<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The exact constable with his original &amp; power in the offices of church wardens, overseers of the poor, surveyors of the highwayes, treasurers of the county stock, and other inferior officers as they are established, both by the common laws and statutes of this realm. By E.W. of Grays-Inn Esq;</title>
            <author>Wingate, Edmund, 1596-1656.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1660</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 101 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 92 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A66659</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing W3013</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R219589</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99831050</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99831050</idno>
            <idno type="VID">35512</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A66659)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 35512)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2087:06)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The exact constable with his original &amp; power in the offices of church wardens, overseers of the poor, surveyors of the highwayes, treasurers of the county stock, and other inferior officers as they are established, both by the common laws and statutes of this realm. By E.W. of Grays-Inn Esq;</title>
                  <author>Wingate, Edmund, 1596-1656.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <editionStmt>
                  <edition>The second edition, with many useful additions.</edition>
               </editionStmt>
               <extent>[8], 172 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for H. Brome at the Gun in Ivy-Lane,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1660.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>E.W. = Edmund Wingate.</note>
                  <note>Copy tightly bound.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Constables --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Police, Rural --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:35512:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>The Exact Conſtable: WITH HIS ORIGINAL &amp; POWER IN THE OFFICES</p>
            <p>Of <hi>Church wardens,</hi> Overſeers of the <hi>Poor, Surveyors</hi> of the <hi>High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes, Treaſurers</hi> of the County Stock, and other inferior Officers as they are eſtabliſhed, both by the <hi>Common Laws</hi> and <hi>Statutes</hi> of this Realm.</p>
            <p>By <hi>E.W.</hi> of <hi>Grays-Inn</hi> Eſq;</p>
            <p>The ſecond Edition, with many uſeful Additions.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Non Nobis nati ſumus, ſed partim Patriae.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>H. Brome</hi> at the <hi>Gun</hi> in <hi>Ivy-Lane,</hi> 1660</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:35512:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:35512:2"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:35512:3"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:35512:3"/>
            <head>TO THE READER.</head>
            <p>IT may ſeem an imperti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent <hi>attempt,</hi> to loaob you with this Treatiſe, there being already one in Print which carries the Face of the ſame <hi>deſign.</hi> But if you compare the <hi>Time</hi> and poſiture of af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fairs, which produced that <hi>Schem</hi> of Laws with the preſent, which gives bee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to this, you may Ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tionally
<pb facs="tcp:35512:4"/>conclude, that thoſe <hi>Rules</hi> for Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in the Civil and Ec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cleſiaſtical affairs are no more proper now then <hi>(The keepers of the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty of</hi> England, <hi>&amp;c.)</hi> are to be the <hi>Supream Magiſtrate:</hi> Thoſe acts of <hi>Obedience</hi> and <hi>Religion</hi> which then were taken for <hi>Graces,</hi> being now juſtly condemned for <hi>Errours</hi> and <hi>Vices.</hi> Not to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flect on the <hi>Author</hi> of the former <hi>compilement,</hi> who being circumſcribed by the wilful Dictates of the perſons then in power, was out of fear or ſomewhat
<pb facs="tcp:35512:4"/>elſe, forced to tune the <hi>Law</hi> as much as he could to their <hi>Tyrannical</hi> ears. Were he now to write on the ſame Subject, he could not, nor would have vari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed a <hi>Tittle</hi> in ſubſtance from what is now expo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed to your view. But the ſame <hi>Garment</hi> which was made for a <hi>Monſter,</hi> cannot fit a man. And therefore this which is here publiſhed, care hath been taken to comprehend all thoſe Rules (and only thoſe Rules) which by the ancient &amp; modern Laws, thoſe Officers to whom it is applied are obliged to
<pb facs="tcp:35512:5"/>obſerve. How well it is performed, is ſubmitted to your Judgment; The compiler having no other deſign, then to throw in his Mite towards the e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtabliſhing the deſired and admirable Government of this Nation, and to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tribute his aſſiſtance to all thoſe Loyal and Active ſubjects, who conform to, and Act under the ſame.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="table_of_contents">
            <pb facs="tcp:35512:5"/>
            <head>THE CONTENTS.</head>
            <list>
               <item>Where High Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles and Petty Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables are Sworn. <hi>Page 6</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Of the Sabbath, and Holy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dayes. <hi>p. 69</hi>
               </item>
               <item>The Conſtables Oath. <hi>p. 76</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Who be Rogues by the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute. <hi>p. 80</hi>
               </item>
               <item>The manner of the Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monial. <hi>p. 84</hi>
               </item>
               <item>The Miniſters Office. <hi>102</hi>
               </item>
               <item>A Conventicle. <hi>p. 110</hi>
               </item>
               <item>The Church Wardens Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty. <hi>p. 115</hi>
               </item>
               <pb facs="tcp:35512:6"/>
               <item>Of Quakers. <hi>p. 138</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Of Superviſors, Survey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ors, and orderers of High-wayes. <hi>p. 143</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Of the deſtruction of Noy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſome Fowl and Vermin. <hi>p. 158</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <p>THis Author hath in Print a very uſeful Piece, called <hi>Juſtice Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vived;</hi> Or, <hi>The whole Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice of a Country Juſtice of the Peace.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:35512:6"/>
            <head>The Offices and Duties of Conſtables, Church-wardens, Overſeers of the Poor and High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes, County-ſtock, Treaſurers, and divers other petty Officers, as they are eſtabliſhed by the common Lawes of <hi>England.</hi>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">Of Conſtables and their Antiquity.</head>
            <p>Conſtables were firſt eſtabliſhed by the Statute of <hi>Winſton,</hi> 1. and by divers other Statutes
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:35512:7"/>ſince: their Office is to be Attendants upon the Common-wealth for the maintenance of the Peace, and are to execute the Warrants and Precepts iſſuing out of Court-Leets, from Juſtices of Peace and Coroners with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in their precincts and li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties; <hi>Lamb.</hi> ſaith, a Conſtable in a hundred and <hi>Franchiſe,</hi> is the Kings Majeſties immedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ate Officer for the ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port and maintenance of the Kings peace. There are two ſorts of Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles; high Conſtables and petty Conſtables; the
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:35512:7"/>high Conſtables are for the whole hundred; and comprehends many pari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhes and villages: hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore there were two high Conſtables in every hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred, as you may read in <hi>Lamb.</hi> and <hi>Dalton;</hi> but at this day, there is but one; the other kind are petty Conſtables, and are only for ſome part of a Pariſh, Village, Hamlet or Tything within the Hundred; for in every Hundred there is a High Conſtable, and every pet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Tything within the Hundred hath his petty Conſtable, or Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:35512:8"/>or ſome under Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer, and the petty Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables command is in part of the High Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables juriſdiction, and his Office by the ancient common Lawes of this Realm is the ſame with the High Conſtable as far as his Precincts extend; in divers Counties they are called by ſeveral ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pellations, as in <hi>War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wick-ſhire</hi> Third borrow, in <hi>Kent</hi> Borſholder, and in other places Burrow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>head or tythingman; and he that is ſo ſworn, is in effect the petty Conſtable of the place.</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:35512:8"/>
            <p>In the beginning of <hi>Edw.</hi> 3 were firſt appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted petty Conſtables for the aide and aſſiſtance of the High Conſtables of hundreds in their own Tythings or Burrows; in ſome pariſhes there are Conſtables, but generally in all there are Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men or petty officers: in ſome places the Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man executes and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands the precepts of the Lord of a Mannor, and he is choſen and ſworn at the Lords Court, and ſome are choſen at the Court Leet by the cuſtome, and they are not compelled
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:35512:9"/>to do any thing, but what time out of mind, they have uſed to do: yet all the aforementioned offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers are comprehended in this word Conſtable.</p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Where High Conſtables and petty Conſtables are ſworn.</head>
               <p>THe making of high Conſtables, may be by Juſtices of Peace at quarter Seſſions or at the Leet, either by the Steward or the grand Inqueſt as the cuſtome is; heretofore they were Sworne in the Sheriffs
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:35512:9"/>Torne. Petty Conſtables are moſt properly choſen by the Steward of the Leet himſelf or the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſts preſentment in the Leet: yet they may be choſen by Juſtices of <hi>Peace</hi> in their quarter Seſſions, and as the cuſtom of the place is, for one or two years, and do uſually take their Oathes where they are choſen, or may,<note place="margin">Dalton. p. 37.38.</note> and ſometimes take their Oaths before a Juſtice of Peace at another time.</p>
               <p>A petty Conſtable may be made by one Juſtice of Peace out of Seſſions,<note place="margin">Lamb. duty of Con. Cook 8.41, 42. Dal. 322, 323.</note> as where one is choſen:
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:35512:10"/>and upon good matter ſhewed to the Juſtices,<note place="margin">21. Edw. 3.2.</note> is taken off, and another choſe;<note place="margin">Mant. ca. 10.</note> or by death of the former Conſtable the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice puts in another, for a preſent ſupply, eſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally when the Quarter Seſſions or Leet are far off.</p>
               <p>There muſt be fit per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons choſen for the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables Office, not Clergy men; for if they be cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen, they ſhall be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged by Writ.</p>
               <p>He muſt be a lay per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, not a woman; for although a maid be a houſe-keeper or dwell in
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:35512:10"/>a houſe where the owner was uſually to ſerve, the office is not to be choſen no more then a Widow can do ſuit in a Leet.</p>
               <p>He muſt be <hi>Idoneus,</hi> one that in ſome mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure hath knowledge to underſtand what belongs to his place; therefore an Ideot or Infant cannot ſerve.</p>
               <p>He muſt be of known honeſty, one that will ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecute his Office without malice or partiality; for a ſcandalous or contenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous perſon cannot be fit,<note place="margin">In Anno 1650.</note> neither can an old or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cripted, ſick, or an impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:35512:11"/>or poor man; It was commanded by the King as a ſpecial directi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on for the Juſtices to chooſe of the ableſt of the inhabitants; Which if obſerved, would be a great furtherance to the courſe of Juſtice through<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out his Majeſties domini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons; but it is the common courſe to put the Office upon the pooreſt and weaker ſort, but they are miſtaken; for all are com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pellable to ſerve this Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice that ſhall be conſtrain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to come to the Leet, except Sheriff, Lawyers, and Attournies, which are
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:35512:11"/>to attend in their ſeveral places and vocations, and if they ſhould, the Law allowes them Writs to diſcharge them.</p>
               <p>Where one is under 21 years, he ſhall not be compelled to ſerve; nor an old man above 70. years, but may ſue out his Writ <hi>Denon ponend. in aſſiſſes. &amp; Jurat. vide ff.</hi> 2 <hi>Herb. Nat. br.</hi> And where a man hath Land in one Hundred, and lives in another, and is choſen to ſerve in the place where the Land lyes, if he hath no houſe where his land lyes, he ſhall not
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:35512:12"/>ſerve; for they are bound to ſerve in reſpect of their reſiancy and not in reſpect of their Land; but if he have houſe in either, and lives ſometimes at one, and ſometimes at the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, he may be made one at either Leet.</p>
               <p>If there be a man choſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen either by Steward of the Leet, or by preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment there that is unfit, or by one Juſtice of Peace out of the Seſſons, the Juſtices at the Seſſions may remove him by their order, and a fit perſon ſhall be there elected and ſworn; but if he that is
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:35512:12"/>ſworn at the Leet be a fit perſon, he cannot be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moved by the Juſtices, but by the Lord chief Juſtice of the Judges of that Circuit, by the opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion of all the Juſtices; neither can cuſtome or preſcription exempt any man that is ſo choſen at the Leet. And if any man be fit and duly cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen in the Leet, he ſhall be there fined, if choſen by one Juſtice out of Seſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, and he refuſe to be ſworn, he may be fined and indicted at the Seſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons.</p>
               <p>A Conſtable may make
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:35512:13"/>a Deputy; for elſe how ſhould the place be ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyed in caſe of ſickneſs or other misfortune? but if there be negligence or miſdemeanor committed by the Deputy, the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable ſhall be reſpon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent and anſwerable for them; Yet if the Deputy be a fit perſon and ſworn into the place, the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty ſhall anſwer for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf; yet it hath been de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livered for Law by the Judges, that this is ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther a Tolleration then Law.</p>
               <p>High Conſtables of Hundreds are conſerva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:35512:13"/>of the Peace in their Liberties and Precincts by the common Law of <hi>England.</hi> 3 <hi>Edw.</hi> 4.9. <hi>Crompt. b. &amp;</hi> 122.11. <hi>Hen.</hi> 7. <hi>fol.</hi> 18. There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the High Conſtables for any affray made at the petty Seſſions, may impriſon the Offendors. <hi>Cook</hi> 11.43, 44.</p>
               <p>In the Limits of their ſeveral Towns are conſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vators of the Peace; all petty Conſtables <hi>Virtute Officii, Bro. Peace. fol.</hi> 127. <hi>Tit:</hi> Affray and for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cible entry; but they can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not take ſurety of the Peace, at the requeſt of
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:35512:14"/>any man; yet they may <hi>ex officio,</hi> cauſe ſuch as are in their preſence, and are about to break the Peace, to find ſureties for the Peace as well be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the affray as after. 12 <hi>Hen.</hi> 7.18. <hi>Crom. b.</hi> 222.</p>
               <p>Any man that ſhall make an affray in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of the Conſtable or Borſholder, threaten to kill or beat another, or ready in an affray to break the Peace, the Conſtable or Borſholder ſhall commit them to the ſtocks or to ſafe cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, and after carry them
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:35512:14"/>before a Juſtice, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſing to give ſurety, may commit them to the Goal. 3 <hi>Hen.</hi> 4.9, 10.</p>
               <p>A Conſtable cannot take a Recognizance, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe he is no Officer of Record; if an obligation, the queſtion is how it ſhall be certified an in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to what Court; and that if ſhould be inconvenient for to give Conſtables ſuch authority, was the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolution of the Lord <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſon;</hi> yet there were other juſtices of opinion, that though they could not take bayl nor Recog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizance; yet they might
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:35512:15"/>take ſurety by obligati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on; for the Peace was preſerved by conſtables long before Juſtices of Peace; but the ancient way of the keeping of the Peace, was by Writ out of the Kings Bench or Chancery.</p>
               <p>Where a Conſtable had found any brake the Peace, by the antient common Law it was thus; all ſuch Offendors the Conſtable might impri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon in the ſtocks, or at his own houſe, according to the quality of the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, until they had been bound by obligation with
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:35512:15"/>ſureties to the King for the keeping of the Peace; which obligation was to be ſealed and delivered to the Conſtable, to the Kings uſe, and the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable was to ſend it into the Exchequer or Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cery, from whence pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs ſhould be awarded to Levy the Debt, if the Peace were broken. <hi>Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>de Finch, Ch.</hi> 127.</p>
               <p>Any Conſtable, petty Conſtables Sheriff, Coro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner or Juſtice of Peace, may by the ancient com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Law, arreſt or impri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon all perſons whatſoe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver that ſhall be violators
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:35512:16"/>of the Peace, in any of their preſences, by virtue of their Offices within their Juriſdictions or Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mits; but they are to meddle only with affrays, aſſaults or batteries, or threatnings to break the Peace: and if they be negligent in their Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, may be indicted and fined for the ſame.</p>
               <p>And if they have com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted or bound over any or breach of the Peace, they muſt attend the Goal delivery or Seſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of the Peace, to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare offences for which they were bound over or committed.</p>
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:35512:16"/>
               <p>The Offices of Sheriffs, Coroners, Stewards, or the Sheriffs Torns of the Leet and of the Court of Pypowders, and all Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices of higher courts were long before the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſt. <hi>Vide Cook</hi> 49. <hi>pars in Praefacio.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>In <hi>Lamb.</hi> 16.17. you may read of many others who were by common Law, that had the cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy of the Peace, and were nominated <hi>Cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>des pacis;</hi> ſome were by election, other by tenure, others were by the Kings Writ, and had their du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration for terme of their
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:35512:17"/>lives, or <hi>quamdiu ſe bene geſſerint;</hi> bt they are all antiquated and obſolete.</p>
               <p>A Conſtable may Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt any that ſhall make any affray; if he flyes into a Houſe and ſhuts the doors, he may Juſtifie his breaking open the doors; &amp; if he flyes from thence in freſh ſuit, he may per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſue him, though in an o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther County; and where two be a fighting, though no hurt done, he may ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prehend them, and make them find ſueties for the Peace; and if any be mortally wounded, he may carry him to the
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:35512:17"/>Goal; for he is not Bayl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able, for the fact is felo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny in caſe the Party dies within a Year and a day.</p>
               <p>If any ſhall aſſault a Conſtable doing his Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, he may upon <hi>ſe de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fend,</hi> Juſtifie the killing of him, if he cannot other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe avoid it.</p>
               <p>If a man be taken in or near the high way Rob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bing, and be brought to a Conſtable, he muſt forthwith bring him be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore a Juſtice of Peace to be examined, and if he finds cauſe, have him to the Goal.</p>
               <p>If any do ſuſpect any
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:35512:18"/>of murder or felony, he ought to bring him to the Conſtable, that he may have him before a Juſtice, with him that ſuſpects him, that upon examination if it be found that there is any probabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity in it, the Conſtable may ſearch for him; and a Conſtable may Arreſt one that is indicted of felony upon his own au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thoritie.</p>
               <p>If any fly for felony, it is the Office of the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable to ſeiz his goods; for if they ſhould be em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bezelled, he muſt anſwer for them; therefore it is
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:35512:18"/>beſt to Inventory them with the teſtimony of his neighbours.</p>
               <p>A Conſtable may com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit any that he ſhall find in adultery or fornicati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on,<note place="margin">1 <hi>Hen.</hi> 7.7.</note> taking company with him to bear witneſs; and where he hath arreſted any, or hath in his cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy any that ought to be carried to Goal, he may raiſe ſufficient ſtrength for his ſafe carriage, or in the interim commit to cuſtody, or to the Goal, and the Goaler ſhall have no fee at this reception.</p>
               <p>When a Warrant ſhall be directed to the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable,<note place="margin">27 <hi>Hen.</hi> 7.39.</note>
                  <pb n="26" facs="tcp:35512:19"/>ſtable, or any other infe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rior officer under him, he muſt uſe all expedition and ſecurity for his appre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>henſion, requiring him in the Kings name to go with him; and if he ſhall deny, he may forthwith commit him to priſon, &amp; reſiſting or making an at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt to eſcape, may ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtifie the beating of him; and if he is willing to go, he may chuſe what Juſtice he will go before; but in caſe it be ground<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed upon a Writ of <hi>Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plicavit,</hi> the Delinquent is compellable to go be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore that Juſtice from
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:35512:19"/>whom the Warrant came, upon which the <hi>Supplica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit</hi> is grounded, and if he refuſeth, he may inſtantly carry him to the Goal; and if the party goeth before ſome other Juſtice of Peace, and puts in bayl in ſome of the Courts at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> whereupon he hath a <hi>Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perſedeas,</hi> the Conſtable or inferiour Officer muſt preſently diſcharge him, keeping the <hi>Superſedeas,</hi> in caſe he be queſtioned by the Juſtice from whom the Warrant iſſued.</p>
               <p>The 21. <hi>Jac.</hi> 8. menti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons all <hi>Superſedeaſes</hi> to
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:35512:20"/>be void, unleſs the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs of the Peace or good behaviour, whereupon ſuch <hi>Superſedeas</hi> is grounded, be granted upon motion in Court, with able Sureties, toappear to the Judges of the ſame Court, upon oath to be aſſeſſed at five pounds land, or ten pounds goods in the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidy-book; the oaths, and names, and places of ſuch ſureties ſhall be en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tered, and remain of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord in the ſame Court, unleſs it appears that the Judges from whence the <hi>Superſedeas</hi> iſſued, doth
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:35512:20"/>deſire ſuch <hi>Superſedeas, bona fide,</hi> by ſome party grieved in Court from whence it came.</p>
               <p>A Conſtable muſt take ſpecial care, having ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſted any man, that he doth not wittingly or neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligently let him eſcape; look what offence the party eſcaping is culpa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble of, the ſame is the Conſtable or inferiour Officer that apprehends him; and it lyes in the power of the Judges to aſſeſs what Fine in their diſcretion they think fit; and if the offence be hai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nous, to the value of their goods.</p>
               <pb n="30" facs="tcp:35512:21"/>
               <p>In <hi>London</hi> the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles ought to be aſſiſtant to the Colledg of Phyſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tians with ſeven miles thereof,<note place="margin">11 Henry 4.24. Stanf. 35 Phyſiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans.</note> for the due Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecution of ſuch Statutes as do concern Phyſitians, Apothecaries and <hi>Chi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rurgions,</hi> as you may read in the Statute of 14 <hi>Hen.</hi> 8. <hi>cap.</hi> 4, 5.23 <hi>Hen.</hi> 8.1.</p>
               <p>A Conſtable may ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt any Purveyour that ſhall take any thing from any of the King Subjects, (unleſs it be for the Kings houſhold) and if he ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>glect his office,<note place="margin">Purvey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our 23 <hi>Hen.</hi> 8.3.28 <hi>Hen.</hi> b. ca. 1.</note> he forfeits twenty pounds; neither
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:35512:21"/>can he take any thing of any perſon, but by the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livery of the Mayor, Bay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liffe, Conſtable, or other ſuch Officer of the place from whence the thing is taken.</p>
               <p>Where any ſhall take any thing for the Kings houſe, it muſt be done by Tailes, or Indentures ſeal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed between the Owner and the Taker in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of the Conſtable or ſome other Officer, and the Owner to be ſatisfied for it, 10 <hi>Edw.</hi> 3. <hi>ca.</hi> 1.</p>
               <p>No Taker ſhall take any kind of proviſions whatſoever without a
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:35512:22"/>Commiſſion, and a blank for the County in which the ſaid ſeveral things are taken, and the prizes thereof ſhall be written,<note place="margin">
                     <hi>1</hi> &amp; <hi>2</hi> Phil. &amp; Mar. c. <hi>9.</hi>
                  </note> to which the Conſtable or other Officer ſhall put his Hand and Seal, and make a breviate thereof in writing,<note place="margin">10 <hi>Edw.</hi> 3. <hi>cap.</hi> 1.</note> containing the proviſion ſo taken, upon pain of an hundred Marks, to give it the Conſtable or other Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer, to deliver it to the Juſtices at the next Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Seſſions.</p>
               <p>If a Purveyor ſhall ſeize any thing to the Kings uſe,<note place="margin">20 <hi>Hen.</hi> 6. <hi>cap.</hi> 8.</note> not exceeding
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:35512:22"/>forty ſhillings, and ſhall not pay ready money for it, the owner of the goods taken may retain them; the Conſtable or other inferiour Officer, being required, ought to aid and aſſiſt the party, whoſe goods are taken, upon the the penalty of the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture of double the va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue.</p>
               <p>Every Offender that ſhall be committed to the common Goal, his com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitment ſhall be at his own charge, his goods ſhall be ſold, and the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verplus paid to him;<note place="margin">21 <hi>Jac.</hi> 28.3 <hi>Jac.</hi>
                  </note> if no goods, a tax ſhall be made
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:35512:23"/>by the Conſtable, and Church-wardens, and two or three other of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitants of the Pariſh where the Offender is taken, which being al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed by a Juſtice of Peace,<note place="margin">Concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning the convey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning of Offendors to Priſon.</note> if any that be taxed refuſe to pay, by warrant from the Juſtice, the Conſtable or other Officer may diſtrain and ſell the goods, rendring the overplus.</p>
               <p>Concerning the execut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the Statute 7 <hi>Jac.</hi> 4.<note place="margin">Beggars &amp; Rogues</note> againſt Vagabonds and Rogues, the Juſtices are to aſſemble twice a year; if occaſion be, oftner;
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:35512:23"/>and five days before the Juſtices may command the Conſtables and other inferiour Officers of all the Hundreds, Tythings and Pariſhes, to ſearch for ſuch perſons, or any other ſuſpected, within their Jurisdictions and Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mits, and ſuch as ſhall be found, bring to the ſaid Juſtices; if upon exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation they ſhall be found of a looſe and idle life, by warrant they ſhall be ſent to the Houſe of Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection, there to be pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed, and ſet on work; and the Conſtables muſt give an account under the
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:35512:24"/>hand of the Miniſter of the Pariſh, what diſſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lute perſons they have puniſhed, or ſent to the Houſe of correction; and if they neglect their du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, the Juſtices ſhall fine them, not exceeding for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſhillings.</p>
               <p>The Church-wardens of every Pariſh ſhall levy money for the relief of the Goal Priſoners,<note place="margin">Priſoners.</note> upon the penalty of five pounds to be paid every quarter to the High Conſtables; and they muſt pay of the ſame at the next Quarter Seſſions to the Receiver that ſhall be appointed by
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:35512:24"/>the Juſtices at their Seſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, upon the like penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of five pounds.</p>
               <p>High Conſtables ought to preſent to the Juſtices the defaults of Watches, &amp; the Kings High-wayes, that there be no ditches or buſhes within two hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred foot on every ſide of the High-wayes; and likewiſe if any ſhall lodge Strangers for whom they will not anſwer; by the Statute of <hi>Winton.</hi> and 13 <hi>Edw.</hi> 1.</p>
               <p>Upon pain of forty ſhillings,<note place="margin">Kings-Bench &amp; Marſhal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſey.</note> the High Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable muſt at every Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Seſſions pay the mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:35512:25"/>for maimed Souldi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, and likewiſe ſuch moneys to one of the Treaſurers of the Shire, as the Church-wardens have paid to him for the Priſoners of the Marſhal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſey and Kings-Bench, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on pain of twenty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, 43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 3.1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 25.</p>
               <p>All popiſh Recuſants ſhall be preſented by the High Conſtables or Church-wardens at the Quarter-Seſſions,<note place="margin">Recu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſants</note> that come not to Church monthly, and the names of their children that are nine years old and up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards, living with their
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:35512:25"/>Parents, and the names of their ſervants, upon the penalty of twentie ſhillings for every default: And if they be indicted and convicted, the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable ſhall have out of their goods fourty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings.</p>
               <p>A Conſtable may com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel any Inn-keeper or Victualer to lodge any Traveller or Stranger,<note place="margin">Inholder</note> by the Statute 5 <hi>Edw.</hi> 4.3.3 <hi>Car.</hi> 1.</p>
               <p>By the 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 3.<note place="margin">Alehon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes.</note> All that keep common Alehouſes, that ſell without Licence, ſhall forfeit twenty ſhillings, which
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:35512:26"/>penalty, after warrant from the Mayor or Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, ſhall be levyed by the Conſtables where the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence ſhall be committ4ed, to the uſe of the poor of the ſame Pariſh by way of Diſtreſſe, and in default of payment to be ſold within 3. dayes, rendring the overplus: It ſhall be a conviction if in the view of ſuch Mayor, or Juſtice, confeſſion, or upon the Oath of 2. Witneſſes, which the Juſtices ſhall adminiſter, and if the offendor have not goods, or pay not the penalty within ſix dayes, the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:35512:26"/>may commit ſuch offendor to the Conſtable to be Whipped; and if the Conſtable or Inferi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our Officer ſhall not exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute the puniſhment, he ſhall be committed to the Goale, until the offendor be puniſhed as aforeſaid, or until the Conſtable ſhall have paid for the neglect of his duty forty ſhillings, to the uſe of the poor of the Pariſh.</p>
               <p>Servants that are re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained in Husbandry,<note place="margin">Servants.</note> muſt be according to the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute 5 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 4. after ſuch retainer, ſhall not depart till the time is ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pired,
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:35512:27"/>or have a Teſtimo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nial under the hand of the Conſtable, or other Officer, with two of the Inhabitants of the Pariſh where they laſt ſerved; and ſuch Teſtimonial ſhall be dated by the Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter, taking two pence for the Regiſtring; and if he be retained in any other ſervice without ſuch Teſtimonial, he ſhall be impriſoned till he procure one; if he get none with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in twelve dayes next af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter his impriſonment, he ſhall be Whipped as a Vagabond.<note place="margin">Dabour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers.</note>
               </p>
               <p>All Artificers or Mecha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nical
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:35512:27"/>Tradeſmen the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable ſhall ſet on work in time of Corn or Hay Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veſt, as are fit to labour by the day; and ſuch as ſhall refuſe, ſuch Officer may impriſon in the ſtocks two days and one night, upon the penalty of fourty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings.</p>
               <p>The Statute 2, and 3 <hi>Phil.</hi> and <hi>Mar.</hi> and 5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 13.<note place="margin">High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes.</note> enables the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables or other Officers, with the Church-ward<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ens, yearly upon <hi>Tueſday</hi> and <hi>Wedneſday</hi> in <hi>Eaſter</hi> week, to call the Pariſh together, and to elect two honeſt men of the Pariſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:35512:28"/>to be Surveyors of the High-wayes, for the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pair of High-wayes lead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to any Market Town, and to appoint ſix dayes for the repair of thoſe High-wayes before <hi>Mid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſomer</hi> next enſuing, and to give notice the next <hi>Sunday</hi> after <hi>Eaſter</hi> ſix dayes, and by the Statutes above recited, muſt have one part of the Eſtate in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dented, and may call the Conſtable to an accompt for the forfeitures, for not amending the High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes, and may levie the ſame by Diſtreſſe, and ſell the Diſtreſſe, returning
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:35512:28"/>the overplus, according to the Statute 18 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 10. And if the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyers ſhall not have levy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and imployed the ſame within a year after the offence committed, ſhall render an accompt before two Juſtices of Peace.</p>
               <p>By the Statute 18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 7.<note place="margin">Hedge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>breakers.</note> Conſtables may, or any inferiour Miniſter, Whip breakers of Hedges, and robbers of Orchards and Gardens, ſtealers of Corn and Wood, as be com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to him by the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice, and if they neglect their duty herein, the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:35512:29"/>may commit them to the common Goale till it be performed.</p>
               <p>Every Conſtable by the Statute,<note place="margin">Plague.</note> 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 31. that neglects their Office in the levying money, as they are appointed by the Juſtices, or other head Officers of Towns incor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portated, for the relief of the poor infected with the Plague, as it hath been Taxed, forfeits for eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry offence twenty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, to the uſe of the poor infected; and a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable or other Officer, if the infection be out of the Town Corporate, Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viledged
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:35512:29"/>Place, or Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket Town, may command perſons infected to keep their houſes; and if the perſons will wilfully go abroad, it is lawful for the Watchmen with violence to enforce them; and if any perſon that is ſo in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fected, or having a ſore running upon him, go a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broad, for the ſaid offence he ſhall be puniſhed as a Vagabond, by the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute 39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 4. and to be bound to the good behaviour twelvemonths.</p>
               <p>The Statute of 7 <hi>Jac.</hi> 11.<note place="margin">Nets, and Setting-Dogs.</note> does give power to Conſtables and other
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:35512:30"/>head Officers, being war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ranted by two Juſtices, to ſearch the houſes of per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons ſuſpected, except 40. <hi>l. per annum</hi> of inheri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance, or worth 400. <hi>l.</hi> in goods, for setting-Dogs, or that keep Nets to take Pheaſants and Partridg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>es, and may take their Dogs, and cut their Nets.</p>
               <p>The Statute of the 8 <hi>Hen.</hi> 6. <hi>c.</hi> 5. commands that there be in every Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty,<note place="margin">Waits &amp; Meaſures</note> Borough, and Market Town, Weights and Meaſures ſealed, at which the Inhabitants may freely weigh. 11 <hi>Henry</hi> 7.4.</p>
               <pb n="49" facs="tcp:35512:30"/>
               <p>Such Merchandize ſhall be forfeited of any Wools,<note place="margin">Merchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dize.</note> or other Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandize that ſhall be ſhipped in any ſuſpected place adjoyning to the water, if there be not In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dentures made between the owner, the Mayor, or Conſtable of that place, 14 <hi>Hen.</hi> 6.5.</p>
               <p>Every Mayor, Sheriff, Bayliff, Conſtable, or any other Miniſter of Juſtice, within any of their Juriſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictions or limits, upon the pain of fourty ſhillings for every default, ought to ſearch once every month at the leaſt, the places
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:35512:31"/>where any unlawful Games ſhall be uſed, and may arreſt and impriſon both the Keepers and the Gameſters; and if any of the Officers aforeſaid ſhall know of any Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deſmen whaſoever, Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riner, Fiſher-man, or Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter-man, that doth play at Tables, Dice, Cards, Tennis, Quoiting, Lo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gating, or any other un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawful Game out of Chriſtmaſs, or out of their Maſters houſe in the Chriſtmaſs, unleſſe by the Maſters licenſe, that hath a 100. <hi>l. per annum,</hi> then ſuch Officers may com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:35512:31"/>them to Ward, till he be bound to the King in Such a ſum as the Officer ſhall think fit, not to uſe the ſame again. 23. <hi>Hen.</hi> 8.3.</p>
               <p>By the Statute 21 <hi>Hen.</hi> 8.3.<note place="margin">Bridges.</note> four Juſtices are au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thorized to make a Tax of money for the repair of any decayed Bridge in the High-way; and this muſt be made by the Conſtable, or two of the ſuffioienteſt Inhabitants of the Pariſh.</p>
               <p>The 23 <hi>Hen.</hi> 8.4. gives power to all Mayors, Sheriffs, Bayliffs, <note place="margin">Veſſels.</note> and Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, (where no Wardens
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:35512:32"/>of Coopers be) to ſearch, view, and gage Barrells, Kilderkins, Firkins, and other Veſſels to be made there, to have the advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage as the Wardens of Coopers in the City of <hi>London</hi> hath.</p>
               <p>The 27 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 14.<note place="margin">Making Malt.</note> doth enable the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles of all Boroughs, or Market Towns, to view, ſearch, and ſervey all ſuch Malt, to be made of ſold; and if any made at any time (except in <hi>June, Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly,</hi> and <hi>Auguſt</hi>) but it ſhall have at the leaſt three weeks in the ſat floor ſteeping, and ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:35512:32"/>drying thereof in the months aforeſaid, ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venteen dayes at the leaſt; and if any ſold that is good mingled with bad, or made of Mow-burnt Barley, or ſpired, or not ſufficiently well trodden, rubbed, or fanned, where half a peck of duſt, or more may be fanned out of one Quarter, then may the Conſtable, with the advice of one Juſtice of Peace of the ſame Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, cauſe the Malt to be ſold to ſuch perſons at reaſonable prices, under the common price of the Market, as to his diſcreti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:35512:33"/>ſhall ſeem meet.</p>
               <p>The 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 2. and 3.<note place="margin">County ſtock.</note> puts the power in the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable and Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens of each Pariſh, if the Pariſhioners diſagree, to Rate and allot within their pariſh, their Aſſeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment for the Shire-ſtock, wherewith the Pariſh was charged at the quarter Seſſions, and may levy the ſame, upon any of the Pariſhoners by diſtreſs and ſale of his goods, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoring the overplus to him.</p>
               <p>By the 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> 7.<note place="margin">Tippling</note> all Conſtables and Church-wardens ſhall in their
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:35512:33"/>Oaths be charged to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent the offences againſt the ſtatute, 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 9. Of all Inn-keepers and Ale<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſe-keepers, that ſuffers any to continue Tippling in their houſes (except labouring men in dinner time, or lodger there, during their work, or up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on ſufficient grounds to be allowed by two Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces) forfeits ten ſhillings to the poor of the Pariſh; or that ſhall vend or ſell leſs then a full quart of the beſt Ale or Beer for a penny, forfeits twenty ſhillings to the ſaid uſe, the offences viewed by
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:35512:34"/>the Mayor, Bayliff or Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice in their ſeveral li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mits, or proved by the Oath of two witneſſes, and according to the 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> 7. one witneſs or his own Oath is ſufficient to convict any; penalty is to be levied by the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles or Church-wardens of the Pariſh where the offences are done; in de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault of payment within ſix dayes, the diſtreſſe to be apprized and ſold, and the overplus reſtored to the party, upon pain of fourty ſhillings to the uſe of the poor, if the duty be neglected.</p>
               <pb n="57" facs="tcp:35512:34"/>
               <p>The 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 29. ſpeaks that all Juſtices of Peace,<note place="margin">Victual<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes.</note> Mayors, Bayliffs, Head-officers, and Conſtables, in Lent-time may enter into all houſes for Victua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, and where any fleſh ſhall be ſuſpected to be dreſſed, and finding any dreſſed in Lent-time, or on Fiſh-days, (except pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided for Ships, or killed three days before Eaſter) may ſeize the ſame as for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feited, and give it to the poor.</p>
               <p>In the 3 <hi>Jac.</hi> 4.<note place="margin">Preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Recu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſants.</note> the Statute enables Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles and Church-wardens to be preſent once every
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:35512:35"/>year at the Quarter Seſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, to preſent the month<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly abſence of Recuſants from Church, and their Childrens Names, nine years old and upwards, living with their Parents, with their Servants, and in default thereof, for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feits twenty ſhillings; and if any of them be indict<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and convicted, (not before convicted) ſhall have fourty ſhillings of the Recuſants goods.</p>
               <p>The 3 <hi>Jac.</hi> 12. inſtructs the Conſtables &amp; Church-wardens of all Market-Towns, Pariſhes, and Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties, where any offence
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:35512:35"/>is committed about the erecting new Wears along the Sea-ſhore, or in any Harbour, Haven or Creek, for the deſtruction of any Spawn or Sea-fiſh, in any Wear, or other Engine, within five miles of the mouth of any Haven, or with fiſhing with any Hay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>net, or Drag-net, under three inches meaſh, may levy the forfeiture by di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs, or ſale of the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendors goods, returning the overplus.</p>
               <p>The 7 <hi>Jac.</hi> 3. enjoynes the Parſon or Vicar of all Towns and Pariſhes,<note place="margin">Appre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tices.</note> not incorporate, with the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:35512:36"/>and Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ens, Collectors, with the Overſeers for the poor, concerning money given for binding Apprentices of the poors Children within their Pariſhes, and they have the placing of them; and to give ſuch monies with them as they ſhall think fit, according to the will of the donor; and if they make default, then every one ſo offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding forfeits three pound: and the Maſter, Miſtriſs, or Dame of ſuch Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tices, ſhall bne bound with one or two ſufficient ſure<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties in double the ſumme
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:35512:36"/>they have received with the Apprentices to the Parſon, Vicar, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pay the mony ſo received at 7. years end, or with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in three months next af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter. And if the Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice, Maſter or Miſtriſs, happen to die within the term, then within one year next after ſuch death the Parſon, Vicar, or Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable, ſhall put forth ſuch moneys within three months after their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipt; and if there be not fit perſons to be <hi>bound</hi> in the Townes and Pari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhes, then in the next Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes adjoyning the poor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt
<pb n="62" facs="tcp:35512:37"/>Children may be placed by the diſcreti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the Parſon, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And that no Apprentice be above fifteen years of age to be bound; and the Parſon, Vicar, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall every year in Eaſter-week, or within a month, give up his account before four, three or two Juſtices of the Peace inhabiting in or next to the ſaid Towns and Pariſhes, for all ſuch moneys as they have im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed in binding of Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices; and of all Bonds and Obligations for the payments thereof:
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:35512:37"/>and the moneys remain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in their hands, they are at ſuch accounts, or ten dayes after to deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver it to their Succeſſors, or ſuch as are in their places, with the bonds and moneys as they have in their hands not im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed.</p>
               <p>The 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> 29.<note place="margin">Curſing and ſwearing</note> doth enable all Officers, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Juſtices of Peace, Mayors, Bayliffs, Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> where any ſhall ſwear or curſe in the hear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of any of the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſad Officers, or ſhall by two witneſſes, <hi>or</hi> their <hi>own</hi> confeſſion before any offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:35512:38"/>where the offence is committed, be convinced by this Act to miniſter an Oath; the offendor for every offence ſhall pay one ſhilling to the uſe of the poor of the ſaid pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh; and it is warranted by this Statute, that the Conſtables, Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens, and Overſeers, may levy ſuch ſums of mony as ſhall be forfeited by di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs or ſale of the off<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>endors goods, rendring the overplus; and if he have no goods, and be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove the age of 12 years, he ſhall be ſet in the ſtocks three hours; if under the
<pb n="65" facs="tcp:35512:38"/>ſaid age, and ſhall not in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtantly pay the 12 pence, then by a warrant from the Juſtice or head offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall be whip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ped by the Conſtable, Parent or Maſter, in his preſence; all offences a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt this Statute, ſhall be done within twenty days after the offence committed.</p>
               <p>By the 1 <hi>Car.</hi> 1.<note place="margin">Propha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning the Sabbath.</note> there ſhall be no meetings or aſſemblies of the people out of their own pariſhes on the Lords day, for any ſports or paſtimes what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, as Bear-baitings, Bull-baitings, or other un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawful
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:35512:39"/>ſports or paſtimes; if any offend herein, the forfeiture is 3<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. 4<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. to the uſe of the poor of the ſaid pariſh where the offence is committed; it is a ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient conviction if it be done in the preſence of any officer, or coufeſſion of the offendor, or one witneſs or more upon Oath: which the ſaid Juſtice or any chief officer by this Act is authorized to adminiſter; and if any of the ſaid Officers find any perſon-offending, by warrant under his hand and ſeal, to the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles or Church-wardens of
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:35512:39"/>the pariſh where the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence is done, to levy the penalty by diſtreſs or ſale of Goods, rendring, the overplus to the offendor; in default of diſtreſs to put the offend or in the Stocks three hours; the offend or muſt be proſecuted with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in one month.</p>
               <p>The 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth all Carriers,<note place="margin">Carrier or Wag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>goner.</note> Waggo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, Carter, Wainman, or Drover that travels on the Lords day, with the forfeiture of 20<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. and all Butchers that kill or ſell any victuals upon that day loſe 6<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. 8<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. The ſummes and penalties after con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viction
<pb n="68" facs="tcp:35512:40"/>before a Juſtice of peace, or any other head-officer by warrant from the Juſtice, may be levy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Conſtable or Church-wardens, to the uſe of the poor where the offence is committed, by diſtreſs &amp; ſale of goods, rendring the overplus; here the conviction ſhall be by view of the Juſtice or other head-officer, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion, or upon oath of two or more witneſſes; the offence to be proſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted within ſix months.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="69" facs="tcp:35512:40"/>
               <head>Of the Sabbath and Holy. days.</head>
               <p>BY the Statute of the 2 and 3 of <hi>Edw.</hi> 6. <hi>cap.</hi> 19. 1 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. and and 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 11. The Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable is enabled to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrain all concourſes of people, that come out of the limits of their own Pariſhes, for any paſtimes whatſoever; And that there be not any Bare<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>baiting, Bull-baiting, En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terludes, Common-plays, or unlawful Paſtimes on the Lords Day, and if any offend herein, by the
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:35512:41"/>view of one Juſtice of Peace in the County, or the chief Officer in a Corporation, by his own confeſſion, or one witneſs upon Oath, before one Juſtice, or ſuch an Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer, forfeits to the poors uſe, 3. ſhillings 4. pence, to be levyed by diſtreſſe and ſale of goods of the Offendor, by warrant from the ſame Juſtice, or Officer, to the Conſtable or Church-wardens of the Pariſh; and in caſe no diſtreſs, the Offendor is to ſit in the ſtocks 3. hours. The proſecution upon this Statute, muſt be with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in
<pb n="71" facs="tcp:35512:41"/>a month of the offence committed; and in caſe the Officer be queſtion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, the General Iſſue is to be pleaded, and any ſpecial matter may be gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven in Evidence, 1 <hi>Car.</hi> 1.</p>
               <p>The 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> 7. ſays,<note place="margin">Drun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kenneſs.</note> all perſons that ſhall be drunk, it ſhall be a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viction upon the view of any Magiſtrate, confeſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, or one witneſſe pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving the ſame; the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture is 5. ſhillings to be paid within one week af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the offence co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mitted to the Church-wardens of the Pariſh, to the uſe of the poor; in default of pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:35512:42"/>to be levyed by di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs or ſale of the offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dors goods, by warrant from the Juſtice, before whom the conviction was; if the offendor is not a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, to be ſet in the Stocks 6. hours; and if the Conſtable or other Officer neglect his duty herein in puniſhing, or levying the forfeiture ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Act, he forfeits 10. ſhillings to the poors uſe, where the offence is committed, to be levyed by diſtreſs or ſail of Goods, rendring the overplus to the offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dor; And all perſons that
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:35512:42"/>ſhall continue tiplingin any Inn, Victualling-houſe, or Ale-houſe in the ſame City, Town or Village where he inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bits, excepting handy-crafts-men and travellers, upon working dayes, one hour at dinner, labourers and workmen, which for following their work, ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>journ or lodge in ſuch houſes, other then for ur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent occaſions allowed by two Juſtices, &amp; the ſame be ſeen by any Mayor, or other Head officer or J. of Peace within their limits, or by Oath or two Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes; but by the Statute
<pb n="74" facs="tcp:35512:43"/>of 2 <hi>Jac.</hi> 5. the Magiſtrates view, his own confeſſion, or one witneſs is ſufficient to convict him; the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture is 3s. 4d. to the poor uſe where the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence is committed, to be levied as aforeſaid; and if the Offendor be not able to pay, to ſit four hours in the Stocks; all theſe offences are to be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented by the Conſtables or Church-wardens before the Juſtices of Aſſize in their circuits, Juſtices of peace in Seſſions, Mayors, Bailiffs, and other Head-officers of Cities and Towns corporate, that
<pb n="75" facs="tcp:35512:43"/>have power to inquire of treſpaſſes, and in Court Leets; they that ſhall be convict the ſecond time, ſhall be bound with two Sureties in Ten pound, to be from thence of good behaviour, but none ſhall be puniſhed by this Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute, unleſs he be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented, indicted, or con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>victed within 6 months after the offence commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted; and the oath of him that confeſſeth the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence, ſhall be a convicti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on againſt any that of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fends at the ſame time.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="76" facs="tcp:35512:44"/>
               <head>The Conſtables Oath.</head>
               <p>YOu ſhall well and tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſerve the Kings Majeſty in the Office of a Conſtable, and ſhall ſee the kings Peace to be well and truly keept to the ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt of your power; you ſhall arreſt all ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons as in your preſence ſhall ride or go armed of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fen ſively, or ſhall commit or make any rito, affray, or other breach of the peace; you ſhall do your beſt endeavour upon com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint to you made, to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prehend all Felons, Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>retors, or Rioters, or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons riotouſly aſſembled;
<pb n="77" facs="tcp:35512:44"/>and if any ſuch offenders ſhall make reſiſtance with force, you ſhall levy <hi>Hue ad Cry,</hi> and ſhall purſue them until they be taken; you ſhall do your beſt en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour that the watch in your town be duly kept, &amp; that Hue and Cry be duly purſued according to the Statute; &amp; that the Statute made for puniſhing vaga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bonds, rogues, and night-walkers, and ſuch other idle perſons coming with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in your liberties, be duly put in execution; you ſhall have a watchful eye to ſuch perſons as ſhall man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nage, or keep any common
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:35512:45"/>houſe or place where un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawful Games are uſed, or ſuch as ſhall frequent ſuch places contrary to the Statute; And you ſhall have a care for the main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining of Archery. At your Aſſizes, Seſſions, or Leet, you ſhall preſent all the Offences contrary to the Statutes, made and provided for the reſtraint of inordinate haunting, and tiplingin Inns, Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verns, and Ale-houſes, and other Victualing pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces for the repreſſing of Drunkenneſs, and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phane Swearing; you ſhall true preſentment make of
<pb n="79" facs="tcp:35512:45"/>all Blood-ſhedding, Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frayes, Out-cryes, Reſcues, or other Offences commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted or done againſt the Kings peace within your limits; you ſhall well and duly execute all Precepts and Warrants to you di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected from the Juſtices of Peace, and others who have authority in this County; you ſhall well and truly, according to your knowledge, power, and ability, do and exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute all other things be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing to the office of a Conſtable, ſo long as you ſhall continue in the ſaid office: So help you God.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="80" facs="tcp:35512:46"/>
               <head>Who be Rogues by the Statute.</head>
               <p>ALL perſons are <hi>Rogues</hi> above the age of ſeven years that ſhall call him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf a Schollar,<note place="margin">Rogues.</note> and go about a begging; Sea-fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring-men not ſuffering Ship-wrack, or having a Juſtices teſtimonial of or neer the place where he landed, if he beggs, or exceeds the time of his Teſtimonial; all that begs, or uſes any ſubtil craft, or unlawful Games or Playes; that pretends skill in Phyſiogonomy and
<pb n="81" facs="tcp:35512:46"/>Palmeſtry, foretels Deſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies or Fortunes, wandring perſons, that call them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves a Proctor, Procuror, Patent-gatherer, or Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lector for any Goal or Hoſpitall, all Fencers, Bearwards, and Minſtrels; all Juglers Tinkers, Ped<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers, Petty-chapmen, or Glaſs-men that wander abroad; all common la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bourers wandring abroad, not having meanes to maintain themſelves, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing able of body to work, and refuſe to work for lawful wages; all freed from priſon, and begs for Fees; all that pretend
<pb n="82" facs="tcp:35512:47"/>loſs by Fire; all (not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a Fellon) that call themſelves <hi>Egyptians.</hi> By the Statute 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 31. ſuch as go abroad wilfully, being infected with the Plague, and are com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded to keep their houſes, although no ſore about them; by the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute of 39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 4. they likewiſe are deemed, and taken to be incorrigible Rogues: the Conſtables and Tything-men of all Hundreds and Pariſhes ſhall upon the apprehend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of ſuch Rogues, with the aid of the Miniſter, and one of the Pariſh,
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:35512:47"/>appoint ſuch Rogues to be whipped until his body be bloody, and ſend him from Pariſh to Pariſh, by the officers to the place where he was born, if it may be known by his confeſſion; if not, then to the Pariſh where he or ſhe laſt dwelt by the ſpace of a year; if that cannot be known, to the place where they paſſed laſt without puniſhment; and after ſuch whipping, ſuch Rogues ſhall have a Teſtimonial ſealed and ſubſcribed by the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable or other Officer with the Miniſter, or any
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:35512:48"/>two of them; the ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance where of ſhall be Regiſtred by the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter in a book upon pain of 5. ſhillings.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The manner of the Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimonial.</head>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="testimonial">
                  <body>
                     <p>
                        <hi>N. W.</hi> a ſturdy Rogue of middle ſtature, aged <hi>16</hi> years, deſcribing the private marks in his face, and the manner of his habit, with the place of his birth and County, and the day of the month be was taken begging, and was there lawfully whip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ped; and is to travel the
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:35512:48"/>direct way, naming the place; and is allowed three dayes for his going home, and no more, at his peril; ſealed and ſubſcri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bed the day and year a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove written.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>By us
<list>
                              <item>
                                 <hi>A. B.</hi> Miniſter.</item>
                              <item>
                                 <hi>W. A.</hi> Conſtable.</item>
                              <item>
                                 <hi>W. E.</hi> Pariſhoner.</item>
                           </list>
                        </signed>
                     </closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <p>And ſuch Rogues that fulfils not the contents of his Teſtimonials, then he or ſhe ſhall be whipped in all places where de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault is made, till they repair to the place ſo ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed: And this Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monial muſt be carried
<pb n="86" facs="tcp:35512:49"/>with them, and it is re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired to put down the ſeveral marks on the bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies of ſuch Rogues, that the Officers may not be deceived: And if he will not be reformed, any two Juſtices of the Peece may commit him to the houſe of Correction, one being of the Quorum.</p>
               <p>The Statute 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 7. commands all perſons to apprehend ſuch Rogues or Vagabonds, as ſhall come to their Houſes to beg Alms, and them to carry to the next Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble or Tythingman, upon the penalty of 20. ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings
<pb n="87" facs="tcp:35512:49"/>for every default.</p>
               <p>All Conſtables, Head-borrows and Tything-men, that ſhall make a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny default in the execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting of their Offices, ſhall loſe for every default ten ſhillings. And by the Statute, 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 7. the Conſtable or Tything-man forfeits twenty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings. And any other perſon that ſhall diſturb any Officer in the execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of his Office againſt Rogues, ſhall forfeit for every default five pound, and be bound to his good behaviour.</p>
               <p>All Conſtables and Ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing-men,
<pb n="88" facs="tcp:35512:50"/>ſhall take and puniſh all Rogues and Beggars that ſhall be ſet a ſhore here fgrom <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, Scotland,</hi> and the <hi>Iſle of Man,</hi> till he come to the next Port or Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh, where he was firſt Landed, upon the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture of ten ſhillings.</p>
               <p>If a Rogue affirms that he was born in ſuch a Town, in ſuch a County, and it appears to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, the Statute then terms him an incorrigible Rogue, and he is to be ſent to the Houſe of cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection; and if there be no Houſe of correction,
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:35512:50"/>then to the Goal until the next Seſſions, and there to be ordered according to the Statute. If the Huſband and Wife have a houſe, and they wan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der up and down the Country, they muſt be ſent to the Town where the Houſe is; and ſo muſt likewiſe Inmates: And the Wife and Children under ſeven years, muſt be ſent to the Huſband; if he be dead, then with the Wife where ſhe was born or dwelt laſt; and the vagrant children a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove ſeven years of age, muſt be ſent to the place
<pb n="90" facs="tcp:35512:51"/>of their birth; and if the vagrant Parents with their children under ſeven years old be placed at the place of their birth, or laſt place of their abode, if it ſhall happen after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards that their Parents die there, or run away, yet the children once ſet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tled muſt there remain, though they grow to the age of ſeven years; and if the Wife be a vagrant Rogue, they muſt be ſent to the Huſband, though a Servant in another place.</p>
               <p>Where any not being Rogues, do travel with their children through a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny
<pb n="91" facs="tcp:35512:51"/>pariſh, if Father or Mother die or run away, the place is not to keep them where they die, nor ſend them away, but on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in charity, except they become wandring Beg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gars.</p>
               <p>And where the Parents have work, they are to find their children with their labour; But where there is not ſufficient, the Pariſh muſt bind them Apprentices according to the Statute.</p>
               <p>None but vagrants ſhall be put out of the Pariſh where they dwell, nor re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leived by the Town, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept
<pb n="92" facs="tcp:35512:52"/>impotent people, but ought to ſet themſelves at work; if they cannot, the Overſeers muſt ſet them at work; And all ſuch perſons as be of abi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity to work, are not to be ſent to their place of birth, or laſt dwelling, by the ſpace of a year, but to the houſe of cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection, according to both the Statutes of the Poor, and Rogues; but if they have any lawful means to live on, though they work not, yet they ſhall not be ſent.</p>
               <p>If any Officer ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>move any out of the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh,
<pb n="93" facs="tcp:35512:52"/>that ought not to be put out, it is againſt the Statute that is provided for the relief of the poor, and ought to be fined, and if any have been ſo ſent, they are to be ſent back.</p>
               <p>Where any if ſent to a Pariſh where he ought, and he is refuſed, whether a ſturdy Rogue or impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent, the forfeiture is five pound; and he that is ſo ſent, is to be left to the Church-wardens and O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſeers; And all Rogues muſt be ſent by a Paſport and conveyed from Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh to Pariſh, as the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:35512:53"/>requires, upon the penalty of five pound. And likewiſe where the Officer will not receive a Rogue to convey him to the place where he was born or laſt dwelt, the forfeiture is five pound.</p>
               <p>None may be permit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to beg by the High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes, though in their Pariſh, nor to take relief at any mans door, in the ſame pariſh, unleſs by the appointment of the Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeers.</p>
               <p>In the word Parents is meant a Father or a Grandfather, Mother or Grandmother, being able
<pb n="95" facs="tcp:35512:53"/>perſons; and in the word Children, is any Child or Grand-child; and all Parſons or Vicars, may relief the poor of their pariſh as well as others that dwell in the pariſh.</p>
               <p>Where any man hath an impropriation of any Tythes, Cole-mynes or Lands in manual Occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pation, is chargeable; and thoſe that have ſaleable Woods, where they re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive any annual benefit, ſhall be taxed to all the aforeſaid payments; and where there is but one Church-warden, it is ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient to charge any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon
<pb n="96" facs="tcp:35512:54"/>with the Overſeers.</p>
               <p>No Juſtice of the Peace are to meddle in the cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing of a Conſtable, ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in Seſſions, or out of Seſſions, where it hath been time out of mind uſed in a Court Leet, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs there hath been ſome neglect, or miſgovern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in the ſaid Court. The Kings-Bench is to decide the difference, if any Juſtice of Peace ſhall intermeddle to remove a Conſtable that hath been choſen by the Leet, and the Leet may put him in again. For there always hath been a queſtion of
<pb n="97" facs="tcp:35512:54"/>the Juſtices power herein, as you may read, <hi>Trin.</hi> 9 <hi>Jac. Ban. Regis,</hi> and in the Report of <hi>Stiles</hi> 362.</p>
               <p>But it hath been agreed by all the Judges, if the Leet do not chooſe a fit man Conſtable, or neglect to give him his Oath, or doth any unlawful act in the chooſing him, the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices may chooſe one; <hi>Steels Rep.</hi> 71. <hi>Mich.</hi> 22. <hi>Car. Ban. Regis.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And if a Conſtable die or be removed, then the Leet, if near, may chooſe one otherwayes; it muſt be done by the Seſſions, or out of Seſſions, by the
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:35512:55"/>two next Juſtices, and the Lord (if any miſcarriage be proved) ſhall looſe his Leet; and this was the Reſolution of all the Judges in 1633.</p>
               <p>But now there is a proviſion made by the 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. that if ſuch offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer either remove or die, any of two next Juſtices, or any other two Juſtices may ſwear a new one to continue till the Leet or quarter Seſſions, and then the Steward of the Leet or Juſtices, are to chooſe or ſwear an other. Or,</p>
               <p>And if a Conſtable have ſerved his Office a year,
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:35512:55"/>the Juſtices at their Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Seſſions may diſcharge him of the Office, and put in another till the next Court Leet.</p>
               <p>You ſhall read <hi>Trin.</hi> 9. <hi>Ban. Regis.</hi> that where there is no Leet for the Hundred, the Juſtices ſhall make High Conſtables, and this hath been con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtantly done by the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Crook</hi> 1. part 283. ſayes, that all Attorneys are priviledged from ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving any Office, and the reaſon is, becauſe they at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend the Kings Majeſties Courts, and if any ſhould
<pb n="100" facs="tcp:35512:56"/>be choſen, the Law allows them a Writ.</p>
               <p>And likewiſe every Servant of the Kings Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties, in ordinary, are priviledged, becauſe they are alwayes ſuppoſed to be attendants upon his Perſon in his Court or affairs. <hi>Vide Reſol.</hi> of the Judges, 1633.</p>
               <p>And if any be choſen to the Office of Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, and refuſeth to ſerve, he ſhall be fined or im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſoned for his con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt, and the Judges of the Kings-Bench may compel him to it if he have not ſome legal im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pediment,
<pb n="101" facs="tcp:35512:56"/>
                  <hi>Vide Crook</hi> 1. 409.</p>
               <p>The office of a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable of a Hundred, may not make a Deputy for the Execution of his Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, yet a Deputy may do many buſineſſes in his Office in the Conſtables name, but the Conſtable ſhall be reſpondent for the ſame. <hi>Vide Reſol.</hi> Judges in 1633.</p>
               <p>Where in ſome Pari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhes or Towns, the cuſtom of the place is, that the Office ſhall go from houſe to houſe, is not good, but yet where there is a cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtome that every man
<pb n="102" facs="tcp:35512:57"/>that is ſufficient in the place, ſhall ſerve the Office, or find a man to do it, may be good, <hi>Crook.</hi> 1.283.</p>
               <p>A Conſtable of one Town ſhall not execute his office in another Town where he is not Conſtable, and the perſon that is ſo choſen muſt be <hi>perſon a habilis &amp; idonea:</hi> Or elſe he may be removed. <hi>vid. le Statutae</hi> 10 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 4.18.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The Miniſters Office.</head>
               <p>THe Miniſter or Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate of every Pariſh ought to Regiſter the Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimonial
<pb n="103" facs="tcp:35512:57"/>of every Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant at his departure out of his ſervice, and two pence is allowed for the Regiſtring.</p>
               <p>He is to aid the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable or Tythingman in the whipping of all Rogues, and to Regiſter them, and to ſend a Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimonial with the Rogue after he is whipped, upon the forfeiture of five ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings for every default.</p>
               <p>He hath power to give Licence to any that is ſick during the time of his ſickneſs,<note place="margin">Licenſe to eat fleſh.</note> to eat fleſh up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on days prohibited, and ſhall have four pence for
<pb n="104" facs="tcp:35512:58"/>Regiſtring the ſame in the Church book, if the parties ſickneſs continues above nine days after the Licence granted: But the Statute 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 29. that no ſick perſon by vertue of 5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 5. is warranted to eat any Butchers meat in Lent, or any other dayes prohibited, but the ſick perſon may incurre the penalty of the ſaid Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute.</p>
               <p>If any perſon ſhall af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter notice given by the Miniſter,<note place="margin">Coming to Church.</note> Curate, or Church-wardens, main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain or keep in his houſe, or any where under his
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:35512:58"/>tuition, any perſon that wilfully refuſeth to come to Church, forfeits ten pound for every month; and by 35 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 1. the the Miniſter or Curate of the Pariſh may require a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny perſon within three months after his convi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, to make publick confeſſion and ſubmiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on in the time of Divine Service on a Sunday or Holy day.</p>
               <p>The 35 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 5. gives power to the Miniſter or Curate of the Pariſh, and to the Conſtable and Ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thingman of any Town, to which any Recuſant is
<pb n="106" facs="tcp:35512:59"/>ſent, to enter the ſame into a book to be kept for the purpoſe, and ſhall certifie the ſame at the next Quarter Seſſions for that County.</p>
               <p>By the Statute of the 3. of King <hi>Jac.</hi> all Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters after morning Pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er or Preaching,<note place="margin">Solem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizing the 5. <hi>Novem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber.</hi>
                  </note> ſhall publickly and diſtinctly read the ſaid Statute con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the miraculous delivery of the King and State from the Powder-Treaſon, giving to Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mighty God a Sollemn Thanksgiving annually, in all Churches within his Majeſties Dominions.</p>
               <pb n="107" facs="tcp:35512:59"/>
               <p>He that ſhall wilfully diſturb a Preacher in his preaching, or ſhall reſcue him that hath ſo done; a Juſtice upon complaint only, for ſix dayes, may commit him to cuſtody; but after the ſix dayes, two Juſtices muſt take the examination, and finding it either by his own con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion, or proof, or by two witneſſes that he is guilty, may commit him to priſon for 3. months. <hi>Vide le Statutae,</hi> 2 <hi>Phil. &amp; Mar. cap.</hi> 3.</p>
               <p>But this Act mentions not whether the evidence ſhall be by Oath, nor im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powers
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:35512:60"/>the Juſtice to give an Oath, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore it is the ſureſt way, to leave the Offendors puniſhment to the Seſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons.</p>
               <p>And if an Offendor a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt this Act, doth make an eſcape, the Town where he eſcapeth, ſhall be puniſhed. But no mention is made in the ſaid Act, whether the evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence ſhall be by Oath; neither are the Juſtices impowered to give an Oath; Therefore it is the beſt way to leave the Offendor to the Seſſions.</p>
               <p>Where any man ſhall
<pb n="109" facs="tcp:35512:60"/>affront, threaten, or force any Miniſter to uſe any other Service, or hinder him in doing the Service according to the Book of Common-prayer (that is by ſundry Acts eſtabliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.) For the 1. offence, ſhall pay 100. Marks, for default of paying within ſix weeks after conviction, impriſonment without Bayl. For the 2. offence 400. Marks, non<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>payment in ſix weeks, 12. months impriſonment without Bayl. For the 3. offence, the loſs of all his Goods, and Chattels, and Impriſonment du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring life.</p>
               <pb n="110" facs="tcp:35512:61"/>
               <p>By the 2 and 3 <hi>Edw.</hi> 6. the firſt offence is ten pound, and for non-pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment after conviction, Impriſonment 3. months without Bayl. For the 2. offence, 20. pound, which if not paid in ſix weeks af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Conviction, impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment ſix months without bayl. 3. Offence the loſs of all his goods and chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, and impiſonment du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring life.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>A CONVENTICLE.</head>
               <p>A Conventicle is de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed by the Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>non,<note place="margin">The de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>finition of a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venticle.</note> to be a meeting of
<pb n="111" facs="tcp:35512:61"/>Miniſters or others, to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſult about any thing that ſhall tend to the depra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation, impeachment, or abuſe of the Doctrine of the Church of <hi>England,</hi> or of the Book of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-Prayer, or of any part of the Diſcipline, or Government of the Church, and by the Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>non the puniſhment is Excommunication, <hi>ipſo facto Can.</hi> 73.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Vide le Statue</hi> 35 <hi>Eli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zabeth</hi> 1. puniſhes all per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons that obſtinately do refuſe to come to Church, and perſwade others to impugne the Queens au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:35512:62"/>in the Law Eccle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiaſtical, and to avoid the inconveniencies of the dangerous practiſes of ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditious, ſchiſmatical and diſloyal ſectaries, or meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings of people, under co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour or pretence of any exerciſe of Religion, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the Lawes and Statutes, <hi>vide Lamberts Juſtice of Peace;</hi> in title <hi>Commiſſion of the Peace:</hi> There he deſcribers it to be a meeting under co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour of exerciſe of Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion, to oppoſe the Kings Authority in cauſes Eccle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiaſtical, or againſt the Laws and Statutes of the Realm.</p>
               <pb n="113" facs="tcp:35512:62"/>
               <p>By this Statute, the Conſtable is commanded to go where he hears their Meetings are, and to car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry them before the next Juſtice, and after being thereof convicted, is to be committed to Priſon, and there to remain with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Bayl, till he conform or come to ſome Church, Chapel, or Place of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-Prayer, to hear Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vine Service according to the Laws and Statutes; And being ſo convicted of this offence, ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe to conform, and come to Church, and to make his ſubmiſſion
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:35512:63"/>within 3. months after, being required by the Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhop of the Dioceſs, Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter of the place, or one Juſtice of the County where he lives, then ſuch perſon at the quarter Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions, or Aſſizes, ſhall there take his Oath to abjure the Realme for ever, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs Licenſed by the King and his Council to retune. And his Adjuration ſhall be certified by the Juſtices to the Judges of Goal-delivery, and if he refuſe to abjure, or departing, return without the Kings Licenſe, ſhall ſuffer as a Fellon.</p>
               <pb n="115" facs="tcp:35512:63"/>
               <p>It is further explained by the ſaid Statute, that he that ſhall abjure, or ſhall refuſe ſo to abjure, being required, ſhall for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit all his good and chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels for ever, and loſe all his Lands and Tenements for life, and no longer; but no loſs of Dower or Corruption of blood, to be in this caſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The Church-Wardens Duty.</head>
               <p>BY the Statute 12 <hi>Hen.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Their office by the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monlaw.</note> 7. <hi>in fine</hi> Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens by the common Law
<pb n="116" facs="tcp:35512:64"/>of <hi>England,</hi> are taken by way of favour to the Church to divers purpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, and as it were for a Corporation, being ena<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled to take Moneys, Goods and Chattels, and may Sue and be Sued for them to the uſe and profits of the Pariſh, ſo that any man may in the time of his Life, or by his laſt will, give and bequeath moneys, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther moveable goods, ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther to the Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens, or to the Pariſhio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners of a Pariſh for the ſeparation of the Church, or for the buying of
<pb n="117" facs="tcp:35512:64"/>Books, Communion Cups, or other Ornaments for the Church; and the Law ſo favourably doth take it, that its not materially needful to expreſs it in apt words or writing; as for example, if one give a Bell, and hang it up in the Steeple, or make a Pew in the Church, and makes no word of writing thereof, yet it is by this Dedicated and given to the Church: <hi>Lib. intra. fol.</hi> 570. 11 <hi>Hen.</hi> 4.12. 8 <hi>Hen.</hi> 7.12.</p>
               <p>The Church-wardens may maintain an appeal of Robbery, againſt him
<pb n="118" facs="tcp:35512:65"/>that ſteals any thing out of the Church, being once in the poſſeſſion thereof, or an action of treſpaſs, as you may read 37 <hi>Hen.</hi> 6.30. <hi>and</hi> 34.11 <hi>Hen.</hi> 4.12. 8 <hi>Edw.</hi> 4.16. and and if the Parſon or Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>car ſhall take any of the Goods belonging to the Church, the Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens may bring their Action, and recover dam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage to the uſe of the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh; and if thoſe Church-wardens dye before the Action be brought, or the Goods for which they ſue be recovered, their ſue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors may bring their Action</p>
               <pb n="119" facs="tcp:35512:65"/>
               <p>And if any of the Church-wardens do waſte the Goods of the Church, the Pariſh may put out thoſe and chooſe new, and the new church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens may bring an action of Accompt againſt the old, and compel them to make ſatisfaction to the pariſh for the wrong they have ſuſtained during their office; and although the cuſtom of ſome pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes is to continue them, ſome one year, ſome two years, ſome three years; yet upon any default in them, the pariſhioners may at any time when
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:35512:66"/>they pleaſe proceed to a new Election, and call them to an account; yet ſhall the former church-wardens have an allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of all ſuch ſummes of money as they have needfully expended upon the church, or upon meet and lawful Ornaments; and this they are com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pellable to do by the Laws Eccleſiaſtical; and they ſhall have allowance of moneys upon their Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts that they have paid for the relief of pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoners in the common Goal, as you may ſee in the Statute 14 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 5.
<pb n="121" facs="tcp:35512:66"/>and of any other thing the Law charges them to do; but in Lands, or the profits thereof they muſt not meddle at all; as if the walls, windows, or doors of the Church be broken, or trees in the church-yard be cut down, or Graſs eaten up; but this belongs properly to the Parſon or Vicar, as you may ſee in the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute, 11 <hi>Hen.</hi> 3.13. 12 <hi>Hen.</hi> 7.77. 13 <hi>Hen.</hi> 7.9.</p>
               <p>All perſons ſhall repair to their pariſh Church,<note place="margin">Coming to Church.</note> ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept they ſhall be hindred by ſickneſs, or any other
<pb n="122" facs="tcp:35512:67"/>lawful excuſe, or to ſome other place where the Common-Prayer is uſed upon Sundays or other days, which are uſually to be kept Holy, and ſhall then and there ſit orderly during the time of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-Prayer and Preach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, upon pain to be pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed, according to the Churches cenſure, and upon the forfeiture of twelve pence for every perſon ſo offending, to be by the Church-wardens, levyed to the poors uſe, of their Goods, Lands, and Tenements; <hi>vid.</hi> 1 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 2.</p>
               <pb n="123" facs="tcp:35512:67"/>
               <p>The Conſtables and Church-wardens of all Pariſhes,<note place="margin">High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes.</note> ſhall every year on Tueſday &amp; Wedneſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day in Eaſter week, call the Pariſhioners together chooſing then two honeſt Surveyors of the High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways, of the ſaid Pariſh, for the year enſuing, which leads to any Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket Town; if they re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe the execution of the office, they ſhall forfeit twenty ſhillings; The Conſtables and Church-wardens ſhall then name ſix days for the amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the ſaid ways before <hi>Midſummer</hi> next,
<pb n="124" facs="tcp:35512:68"/>giving knowledge of the ſaid ſix days the next Sun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day after <hi>Eaſter,</hi> and ſhall call the Conſtable to an account, having one part of the Eſtreats indented.</p>
               <p>Where any ſhall eat fleſh,<note place="margin">Eating fleſh.</note> either in Lent, or any other days obſerved for Fiſh-days, he forfeits three pound for every offence, or ſhall ſuffer three months impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; and every perſon in whoſe houſe any of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence ſhall be done, being privy, and having know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge thereof, not diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cloſing the ſame to an officer that hath power to
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:35512:68"/>puniſh, ſhall forfeit for every offence fourty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings; the third part of all the forfeits ſhall be to the uſe of the poor of the Pariſh, where the offence is committed; after con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viction, to be levyed by the Church-wardens, as you may read, 5 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 5.</p>
               <p>All Licences that are to be given by the Biſhop of the Dioceſs,<note place="margin">Licence to eat fleſh.</note> or by the Parſon, Vicar or Curate, in caſe of ſickneſs, ought to be Regiſtred, if the ſickneſs continue above 8. days after it is granted, in the Church-Book, with
<pb n="126" facs="tcp:35512:69"/>the privity of one of the Church-wardens there, and the party that is Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenced, ſhall give four pence for it. <hi>vid.</hi> 5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 5. the duties of Miniſters before.</p>
               <p>A Juſtice of Peace may appoint the Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens,<note place="margin">Poor.</note> and 4, 3, or 2 of the Pariſh, to be overſeers of the poor; and they may by conſent of the Major part of them, take order for the ſetting mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried or unmaried perſons on work, that have no means or ordinary trade to live by; and the Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of ſuch Parents as
<pb n="127" facs="tcp:35512:69"/>ſhall be unable to main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain them, and may ſet up any Trade or Myſtery for that purpoſe, and may Tax as well Inhabitants as Occupiers of Lands in the Pariſh to pay weekly ſuch ſumms of moneys as they ſhall think meet for a ſtock, for the releifof the impotent poor there, &amp; for to put out Apprentices of ſuch Children; And they to whom they ſhall be put, ſhall take, receive, and keep them as Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices, and may do a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny thing concerning the premiſes, as they ſhall think meet, <hi>vid.</hi> 1 <hi>Jac.</hi>
                  <pb n="128" facs="tcp:35512:70"/>51. 2 <hi>Jac.</hi> 28. 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 4.</p>
               <p>The Church-wardens, and Overſeers ſhall ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der an account before two Juſtices of Peace of their Money, ſtock and other things concerning their Office, and ſuch Moneys as ſhall be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maining in their hands, to the new ones that are choſen in their places, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the forfeiture of twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſhillings, for every monthly default, without cauſe to be ſhewn and allowed by two Juſtices.</p>
               <p>The Church-wardens and Overſeers are im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powred by the ſaid Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture,
<pb n="129" facs="tcp:35512:70"/>by warrant under two Juſtices hands, to levy all taxations by diſtreſſe and ſale of their goods, as ſhall be found in de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault, rendring the over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plus to the party, and may with the Licenſe of the Lord of the Mannor erect convenient houſes for the poor of their pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh at their general char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges; and when the year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Stock is aſſeſſed by the Juſtices at the quarter Seſſions, it ſhall be by the agreement of all the pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh; and in default, by the Church-wardens and conſtables of the Pariſh,
<pb n="130" facs="tcp:35512:71"/>or the Major part of them, who may levy the ſame by diſtreſs and ſale of the goods of ſuch as refuſe to pay their part, rendering the overplus to the own<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers; and the Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens or Overſeers muſt pay it to the high Conſtable within whoſe limit the Pariſh is ſcituate ten dayes before the end of every quarter Seſſions, ſuch Moneys as the Pariſh ought to pay for the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lief of the priſon in the Marſhalſey, and Kings Bench, upon the pain of ten ſhillings for every de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault of payment.</p>
               <pb n="131" facs="tcp:35512:71"/>
               <p>By the 43 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 3.<note place="margin">Souldi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys.</note> if the Pariſhioners agree not to the rate for the maintenance of diſabled ſouldiers, the Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Conſtables of the Pariſh, or the Major part of them may levy ſuch rates by diſtreſs and ſale of their Goods, of a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny that refuſe to pay, ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dring the overplus; which muſt be collected and paid over to the High Conſtable, within whoſe Hundred the Pariſh is; and all ſuch ſumms of Moneys as are collected ten days before every quarter Seſſions of the
<pb n="132" facs="tcp:35512:72"/>peace upon the penalty of twenty ſhillings for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very default.</p>
               <p>The Statute of 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 9. ſays, that if Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables and Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens neglect their office in puniſhing Inn-keepers, Victuallers, and Ale-hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, by the ſpace of twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty days in certifying their defaults, they ſhall for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit twenty ſhillings to the poors uſe.</p>
               <p>The Statute of 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 27. inhibits all per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons to keep any Grey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hound for the courſing of any Hair or Deer, or any ſetting Dogs, or Nets for
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:35512:72"/>the taking of any Phe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſants or Partridges; the Church-wardens have po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wer by this Act, where the offence is commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, to receive to the uſe of the poor of the Pariſh fourty ſhillings. 3 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 4. enables the Church-wardens and Conſtables of all Towns, and Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes, to preſent in the quarter Seſſions, or at the Aſſizes, the monthly ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of Recuſants from Church; and they are to certifie the names of their children above nine years old, and the names of their Servants, upon the
<pb n="134" facs="tcp:35512:73"/>forfeiture of twenty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings; and if upon the Inditement they be convi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted, they ſhall have four<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſhillings out of their goods; and the Church-wardens may be Warrant from one Juſtice of Peace, levie to the uſe of the poor, the offendors Goods, by diſtreſs or ſale, rendring the overplus; and the forfeiture is 12. pence for every default, in not coming to Church every Sunday, according to the Statute 1 <hi>Eliza. ca.</hi> 2.</p>
               <p>By the Statute of 1 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 2.<note place="margin">Abſence from Church.</note> the Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens may levie to the uſe
<pb n="135" facs="tcp:35512:73"/>of the poor, where the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault is, twelve pence; by warrant from one Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice of Peace, by ſale of the Goods of the offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dor, rendring the over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plus, for not coming to Church every sabbath day.</p>
               <p>The Statute of 3 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 10. ſays,<note place="margin">Offendors conveyed to priſon.</note> that the Conſtable and Church-warden with two or three of the Pariſhioners may make a Tax, where an offendor is committed to priſon, and hath not ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient for his conduction thither.</p>
               <p>The Statute of 21 <hi>J.</hi> 18.<note place="margin">Clothing</note>
                  <pb n="136" facs="tcp:35512:74"/>ſays, the Clothier that makes any cloth that is not good and warranta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble by that Statute, for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feits five pound by a war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant from two Juſtices or more; the Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Overſeers of the poor of the Pariſh where the default is commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, may levie the penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty for every cloth deceit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ably made, by diſtreſſe and ſale of their Goods, rendring the overplus; the diſtribution is to the poor of the ſaid Pariſh; and where no diſtreſs is, the offend or ſhall be com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to the Goal, until
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:35512:74"/>payment be made to the Church-wardens and O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſeers, to the uſe above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid: And they to be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comptable for thoſe mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys, as they are for other moneys, which is by them collected for the poor; <hi>vid.</hi> 43 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 3. and by the Statute 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 18. Two third parts of the forfeitures for what of length, breadth, or weight of Cloths by any other Statute now in force, ſhall be levied, di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtributed, and accounted as the forfeiture afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="138" facs="tcp:35512:75"/>
               <head>Of Quakers.</head>
               <p>THe Statute of the 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. <hi>cap.</hi> 2. ſayes,<note place="margin">The difinition of a Quaker</note> that <hi>Quakers</hi> by this Act, are ſuch perſons as holds dangerous Opinions, and ſuch as holds, that the ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of an Oath in any caſe whatſoever, although before a lawful Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrate, is altogether unlaw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful, and contrary to the Word of God; And do refuſe an Oath lawfully rendred.</p>
               <p>That if any perſon who ſhall maintain, that the taking of an Oath in any
<pb n="139" facs="tcp:35512:75"/>caſe whatſoever, before a lawful Magiſtrate is un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawful, and againſt the Word of God, and ſhall wilfully refuſe an Oath, bound to take, being du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly tendred to him; or ſhall perſwade or endeavour to perſwade any other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to whom it ſhall be tendred, to refuſe to take it; or ſhall by Printing, Writing, or otherwiſe go about to maintain or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fend that the taking of it is unlawful; or the ſaid per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons called by the name of <hi>Quakers,</hi> ſhall go from the places of their dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings,
<pb n="340" facs="tcp:35512:76"/>and aſſemble to the number of 5. or more, of 16. years old and upwards at one time, and in one place, under pretence of joyning in a Religious worſhip (not Authorized) by the Law of the Realm) being convict by the ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict of 12. men, or his own confeſſion, or the notorious evidence of the Fact; For the firſt offence ſhall forfeit any ſumme, not above five pound, to be levied by diſtreſs and ſale of his Goods, by war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant of the parties before whom the conviction, ſhall be for want of diſtreſſe or
<pb n="141" facs="tcp:35512:76"/>non-payment in a week, to be committed to the common Goal, or Houſe of Correction for three months without Bayl, to be kept at hard labour.</p>
               <p>For the ſecond offence, the forfeture is 10. pound by diſtreſs, to be levied as aforeſaid, for non-pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in that time, to be committed 6. months to the places before menti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned; the moneys to go for a ſtock to the Houſe of Correction, as the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices ſhall appoint. The 3. offence is Abjuration, after a 2. Correction, or at his Majeſties pleaſure
<pb n="142" facs="tcp:35512:77"/>to be tranſported to any of his Plantations beyond Sea.</p>
               <p>The Judge of Aſſize of Oyer, or Terminer, and Juſtices of Peace in their open and general Seſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, may hear and deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine theſe offences, and as in caſes of treſpaſs, and may make out proceſs in order to their conviction; any Juſtice of Peace, Mayor or chief Officer, may commit to the Goal, or bind over with ſureties to the quarter Seſſions, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny offending in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes; and the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble is the immediate offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ce
<pb n="143" facs="tcp:35512:77"/>to make diligent ſearch in all places within his juriſdiction, for the apprehenſion.</p>
               <p>He that ſhall take the Oath that he formerly re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſed, giving ſecurity not to meet again, although convicted, ſhall be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Of Superviſors, Survey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ors, and Orderers for the High-ways.</head>
               <p>BY the Statutes 2 and 3 of <hi>P.</hi> and <hi>M. cap.</hi> 8.5. <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 13.18. <hi>Elia. cap.</hi> 18.<note place="margin">High-wayes.</note> Every per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon upon ſix days appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted
<pb n="144" facs="tcp:35512:78"/>for working in the High-ways, that hath a plough-land either in til<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage or paſture, in occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pation in the ſame pariſh, and every other perſon keeping there a plough or draught, ſhall find and ſend at every day and place appointed for the amending of the ways in the Pariſh aforeſaid, one Wain or Cart furniſhed with Oxen, Horſes, or other cattle, with other neceſſaries convenient for that purpoſe, and two a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble men with the ſame upon forfeiture of ten ſhillings; and every Cot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tager
<pb n="145" facs="tcp:35512:78"/>and Labourer of the ſaid Pariſh, that is not a ſervant hired by the year, ſhall labour upon eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of the ſaid 6. days: The default of every perſon for every day, is 12. pence; and if there ſhall be no need of an of the ſaid carriages, then the perſons that ſhould have ſent them, ſhall ſend to the ſaid work, to able men for every carriage ſo ſpa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, upon the pain of one ſhilling for every one that ſhall make default: bring<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with them all things materials for ſuch ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice; and all ſhall work
<pb n="146" facs="tcp:35512:79"/>by the ſpace of eight hours, unleſs they ſhall be other-ways licenſed by ſaid Superviſors, or any one of them; and it ſhall and may be lawful for a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of the Superviſors, or any one of them, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the 2 and 3 of <hi>Phil.</hi> and <hi>Mar.</hi> for the better amendment of the High-ways, within the limits of the ſaid Pariſh, to give power to any to take and carry away any rubbiſh, or any broken ſtones of a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Quarry that ſhall lye within the Pariſh, without licenſe or controlement of the owner or owners,
<pb n="147" facs="tcp:35512:79"/>ſo much as in their diſcre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion ſhall ſeem meet and neceſſary; and for default of ſuch Quarries, the Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perviſors or Overſeers, may appoint any to dig gravel or ſand in any grounds lying next the High-ways, within the ſaid Pariſh, ſo much as they ſhall think meet and neceſſary for the repara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions aforeſaid; or any ſtones, or other ſtuffe where heretofore they have uſually digged.</p>
               <p>It is provided in the ſaid Act,<note place="margin">Houſe, Garden or Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard.</note> that the Super<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſors ſhall not dig in any Quarry or Quarries, but
<pb n="148" facs="tcp:35512:80"/>ſhall take ſuch rubbiſh or other materials, fit and uſeful for the High-ways, as there ſhall be found without the licenſe and commandment of the owners; neither impower any to digg and gravel, ſand, of any other thing, in the houſe, garden, or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard or meddow of any perſon or perſons whatſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever; neither in any in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cloſed ground, then only one hole or pit for gravel as afore declared, in breadth or length, above ten yards at the moſt; and then that every ſuch pit ſo digged, the Super<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſor
<pb n="149" facs="tcp:35512:80"/>or Superviſors ſhall within one month after, cauſe to be filled up with earth, at the coſt and charges of the ſaid pariſh, upon the forfeiture of five marks to the owner or owners of the ſoyle.</p>
               <p>By the Statute 5 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 15.<note place="margin">Water-courſes.</note> where any water-courſe ſhall be in any ditch or ditches of the High-ways, it ſhall and may be lawful for the Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perviſor or Superviſors, to to turn the ſame into any mans ground, or ſoyl in ſuch ways, and manner, as to their diſcretion ſhall ſeem moſt meet and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient;
<pb n="150" facs="tcp:35512:81"/>and the Super<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſor or Superviſors, by force of this Act, may within one month after a<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ny default, preſent the ſaid offence to the next Juſtice of Peace, upon the forfeiture of fourty ſhillings.</p>
               <p>The 18 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 10.<note place="margin">Land in ſeveral Pariſhes.</note> declares that every perſon or perſons, (except ſuch as dwell in the City of <hi>London</hi>) that ſhall be aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed to any ſubſidies in Kings books to five pound in Goods, or fourty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings in Lands or above, during the time he ſhall ſtand ſo charged, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="151" facs="tcp:35512:81"/>non of the parties ſo charged for the amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the High-ways, by any other Act, but as a Cottager, ſhall find two able men yearly to labour in the High-ways, as is li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mited and appointed by the ſaid Acts; and all per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons that ſhall uſe or occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pie either in tillage or pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſture, any plough-land that lies in ſeveral pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes, ſhall be chargeable to the ways in the pariſh where he inhabits, as far forth as any perſon having a plough-land in any one pariſh; and every perſon or perſons, that ſhall uſe
<pb n="152" facs="tcp:35512:82"/>any plough-lands in ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Towns or Pariſhes, ſhall find in each Town or Pariſh one Cart-wain, Dung-pot or Dragg, fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed for the amendment of the high-ways within the ſeveral pariſhes where <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> and lyes, in the ſame manner as if he were an inhabitant in the ſaid Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh.</p>
               <p>The 5 of <hi>Eliz.</hi> makes mention,<note place="margin">Scow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling Ditches.</note> that every per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons that re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pairs not, or ſcowrs not his Ditches or Hedges ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyning to the High-way, or leading to any Fair or Market, or cuts down or
<pb n="153" facs="tcp:35512:82"/>keeps under his Trees or Buſhes growing next the High-ways, ſhall forfeit or loſe for every default ten ſhillings.</p>
               <p>And all and every per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons that ſhall uſe any lands next the High-way, or leading to any Fayr or Market, that ſcowr not the Ditches as oft as need ſhall require, whereby the water may be conveyed from the High-way, over the ground next adjoyning, may paſs over the ground next, upon the forfeiture for every Rod next ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyning, not cleanſed
<pb n="154" facs="tcp:35512:83"/>and ſcowred, twelve pence.</p>
               <p>If any perſon or perſons that ſhall caſt any ſoyl or make any dung in any High-way leading to any Fayr or Market-Town,<note place="margin">Banks in High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes</note> letting it lye there by the ſpace of ſix monthes to the annoyance of the way, the Inhabitant ſhall for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit every load there lye<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing twelve pence. And where any hath been caſt into the Highway leading to a Fayre or Market Town, ſo that there is a bank between the land Way and Ditch, the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyours or Workmen ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed
<pb n="155" facs="tcp:35512:83"/>for the amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the High-ways, are to make Sluces or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther devices by their di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcretions to convey the water out of the ſaid way into the Ditch, any law, right, Intereſt, Cuſtome or uſuage to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>The Surveyor,<note place="margin">Indeſault of Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors, Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles or Church-wardens may.</note> or Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors have power by this Statute to levy every ſum or ſums of money forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted within the pariſh, by diſtres in the ſame man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner as Fines, or Amerce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments in Court-Leets have been uſed; and the money to be imployed upon the
<pb n="156" facs="tcp:35512:84"/>High-way that leads to any Fayr or Market-Town where the offence is committed; if the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors do not levy and imploy it within one year after the offence is com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted; that then the ſums or forfeitures ſhall be levyed by the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles or Church-wardens of the Pariſh where the work ought to be done in the High-ways; and that then he or they that ſhall levie any ſuch penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties or forfeitures, ſhall make their account as the afore-mentioned Statutes recite.</p>
               <pb n="157" facs="tcp:35512:84"/>
               <p>The Statute 39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 2. <hi>cap.</hi> 19.<note place="margin">Iron<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>works.</note> enables the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors within the Countie of <hi>Kent, Suſſex,</hi> and <hi>Surry,</hi> where the High-waies ſhall be moſt an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noyed, where the Juſtices have not aſſigned in what place or places of the High-waies there ſhall be carried Gravel, Stone, or Chaulk, to appoint the Occupiers of the Iron<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wors to carrie the ſame, upon the penaltie of for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieſhillings; and the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors ſhall make de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands of all the forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures of money to be paid in default of ſuch Carri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ages;
<pb n="158" facs="tcp:35512:85"/>and ſhall make a true preſentment of all ſuch defaults of payment at the next Quarter-Seſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of the Countie, upon the ſame penalty of four<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie ſhillings.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Of the deſtruction of noy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſom Fowl and Vermin.</head>
               <p>THe Statutes 18 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 15. 14 <hi>Eliz. ca.</hi> 11. 39 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 18. 24 <hi>Hen.</hi> 8. appoints diſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>butors, and gives them orders to pay thoſe that ſhall deſtroy any noyſom Fowl or Vermin in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner
<pb n="159" facs="tcp:35512:85"/>following; Any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon that ſhall bring to them any heads of old Crows, Choughs, Pyes, or Rooks, taken within their ſeveral Pariſhes: E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very three heads one pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nie; for the heads of eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rie ſix young Crows, Pies, or Rooks, taken as a fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, one pennie; for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very ſix Eggs of any of them, one pennie; for everie 12. Stares heads, one pennie; all which ſhall be kept in ſome ſit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting place, and be brought forth once a month at leaſt, before the Church-wardens and Taxers, or
<pb n="160" facs="tcp:35512:86"/>any three of them, and then ſhall make an ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count to them in writing, what money they have laid forth and paid for ſuch heads and eggs, and for the heads of ravenous birds and vermin, as in the ſaid Acts mentioned; for every Merton, Hawes, Furſe-kite, Mold-kite, Buzzard, Cormerant or Ring-tail, two pence; for two eggs of them one pennie; every Iron of Oſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prays-head, four pence, every Woodal, Pie, Jay, Raven, or Kite one pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nie; every Kings-fiſher one pennie, every Bulfinch or
<pb n="161" facs="tcp:35512:86"/>Bird, that ſpoils the buds of Fruit one pennie, eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Fox or Grey, 12. pence, every Fitchew, Polcat, Weaſel, Stote, Faire, Bad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger, Wildcat, one pennie; every Otter or Hedghog, two pence; every three Rats heads or Mice, one pennie; Every Molewarp or Want, an half pennie; the head of all the Birds or Vermine laſt mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, the diſtribution ſhall pay and give to the bring<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er of them, for everie head taken within their Pariſh, and ſhall keep the ſame to be ſhewed forth upon their accompt as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid;
<pb n="162" facs="tcp:35512:87"/>all which ſaid heads and eggs, ſhall be forthwith after ſuch ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compt made in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of the ſaid Church-wardens &amp; Taxers, or of three of them, burned, co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſumed, or cut in ſunder.</p>
               <p>And if upon accompt that there ſhall be any Monies in the hands of a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of the diſtributors, the ſame ſhall then be deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered over to ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons as ſhall be elected and choſen for the year enſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, by bill indented as aforeſaid; provided al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>waies that this ſhall not
<pb n="163" facs="tcp:35512:87"/>extend to give any liberty, li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſe or authority, to any perſon or perſons whatſoever to uſe or exerciſe any menas, or enquire for the deſtruction of Crows, or Rooks, Choughs, or other Vermine aforeſaid, in any place or places, to the deſtruction or diſturbance of the building or breeding of any kind of Hawks, Hernes, Egrits, Paupers, Swans or Shovelers, to the hurt and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction of any Doves, Dove-houſes, Deer, or Warren, or Conies, nor to give or ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point any ſum or ſums of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney to be given, paid or di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtributed to any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons of the Heads of any Buz<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zard, Ringtail, Herne, Polcat, Fitchew or Stote, that ſhall or may be taken in any War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ren or ground imployed for
<pb n="164" facs="tcp:35512:88"/>Conies, or to the taking of a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Stares in Dove-houſes, neither to the deſtruction or bringing of any Kite or Ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven killed in any City or Town Corporate, or within two miles of the ſame.</p>
               <p>There are two Statutes made in the aid and aſſiſtance of Conſtables and Church-wardens; one 7 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 5. the other 21 <hi>Jac. cap</hi> 5. the ſum and effect of both which Statutes are as followeth: The firſt declares that whereas there are many cauſeleſs and contentious ſutes commenced againſt Juſtices of the Peace, Mayors of Cities, or Bayliffs; of Corporate Twons, Head-burrows, Conſtables, Colle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctors of Subſidies, and Fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teens, that have been moleſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed or troubled for the execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
<pb n="165" facs="tcp:35512:88"/>o their Office, by con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tentions and ill-diſpoſed per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, to their diſcouragement in the execution or doing their offices, it is enacted by the ſaid 7 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 5. that if any Action, Bill, or Suite, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count on the caſe, Treſpaſs, Battery, or falſe Impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment ſhall be brought after fourty days next after the end of that Seſſion of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, in any of his Majeſties Courts at <hi>Westminster</hi> or elſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where againſt any Juſtice of Peace, Mayor, Bayliff, of any City, or Town, Corporate, Head-burrow, Conſtable, Ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing-man, Collector of Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidy or Fifteens, for or con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning any matter or cauſe by them or any of them done by vertue of their or any of their office or offices, that it
<pb n="166" facs="tcp:35512:89"/>ſhall be lawful to or for any ſuch Juſtice of Peace, Mayor, Bayliff, Conſtable, or other Officer or Officers before na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med, and all others; that in in their aid and aſſiſtance, or by their commandment, ſhall do any thing touching or con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning his or their Office or Offices, to plead the general iſſue that he or they are not guilty, and to give ſuch ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cial matter in evidence to the Jury, that ſhall try the ſame, which ſpecial matter being pleaded, had been a good and ſufficient matter in Law, to have diſcharged the ſaid de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant or defendants of the treſpaſs, or the other matter laid to his or their charge; and that if the verdit ſhall paſs with the ſaid defendant or defendants, in any ſuch
<pb n="167" facs="tcp:35512:89"/>actions, or the Plaintiff or Plaintiffs become Nonſuite, or ſuffer any diſcontinuance thereof, that in every ſuch caſe the Juſtice or Juſtices, or other Judges, before whom the ſaid matter ſhall be tryed, ſhall by force and vertue of this Act, allow unto the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant or defendants, his or their double coſts, which he or they ſhall have ſuſtained by reaſon of their wrongful vex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ation, in defence of the ſaid Action or Suite, for which the defendant or defendants, ſhall have like remedy as in other caſes, where coſts by the Laws of this Realm are given to the defendants. And this Act is to continue for ſeven years, and from thence to the end of the next Parliament, after the ſaid Parliament.</p>
               <pb n="168" facs="tcp:35512:90"/>
               <p>The other Statute being 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 12. declares the afore recited Statute of 7 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 5. to be perpetual. And that all Church-wardens and all perſons called Swornmen, executing the office of <hi>Church-wardens,</hi> and all overſeers of the Poor, and all others which in their aide and aſſiſtance, or by their commandment ſhall do any thing touching his or their Office or Offices, ſhall hereafter be enabled to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive, and have ſuch benefit and help by vertue of the ſaid Act, to all intents and conſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions and purpoſes, as if they had been ſpecially named therein.</p>
               <p>And whereas notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing by the ſaid Statute, the Plaintiff is at liberty to lay his account, which he ſhall bring
<pb n="169" facs="tcp:35512:90"/>againſt any Juſtice of Peace, or other Officer in any for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rain County at his choice, which hath proved very in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>convenient unto ſundry of the Officers and perſons afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, that have been impleaded by ſome contentions &amp; trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bleſome perſons in Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties far remote from their places of habitations: It is en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted by this Statute, that if any Action, Bill, Plaint or Suit upon the caſe, Treſpaſs, Bat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tery or falſe Impriſonment ſhal be brought after the end of this Seſſion of Parliament, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt any Juſtice of Peace, Mayor or Bayliff of City or Town Corporate, Head-bor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row, Conſtable, Tythingman, Collector of Subſides or Fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teens, Church-wardens and perſons called Swornmen, exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuting
<pb n="170" facs="tcp:35512:91"/>the Office of Church-wardens or Overſeers of the Poor, and their Deputies or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of them, or any other which in their aid and aſſiſtance, or by their commandment ſhall do any thing touching or concerning his or their Office or Offices for, or concerning any matter, cauſe; or thing, by them or any of them done by vertue or reaſon of their or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of their Office or Offices: That the ſaid Account, Bill, Plant or Suit, ſhall be laid within the County, where the Treſpaſs or Fact ſhall be done and committed, and not elſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where: And that it ſhall be lawful to, and for all and eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry perſon and perſons afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, to plead there unto the general iſſue, that he or they are not guilty, and to give in
<pb n="171" facs="tcp:35512:91"/>ſuch ſpecial matter in evid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence to the Jury, which ſhall try the ſame as in and by the ſaid former Act, is limited and declared: And that if up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the tryal of any ſuch Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, Bill, Plant or ſuit, the Plan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff or Plantiffs therein ſhall not prove to the Jury which ſhall try the ſame, that the Treſpaſs, Battery, Impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment or other fact or cauſe of his, her or their ſuch accounts, Bill, Plant or Suit, was or were had, made, committed or done within the County, where ſuch account, bill, plant or ſuit ſhall be laid: That then in every ſuch caſe the Jury which ſhall try the ſame, ſhall find the defendant and defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dants in every ſuch Account, Bill, Plant, or Suit, not guil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, without having any regard
<pb n="172" facs="tcp:35512:92"/>or reſpect to any evidence gi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ven by the Plaintiff, or Plan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiffs, therein touching the Treſpaſs, Battery, Impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, or other cauſe, for which the ſame Account, Bill, Plant or Suit, is or ſhall be brought: And if the verdict ſhall paſs with the defendant or defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dants, in any ſuch Account, Bill, or Plaint or Suit, or the Plantiff or Plantiffs, therein become Non-ſuit, or ſuffer a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny diſcontinuance thereof, that in every ſuch caſe, the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant or defendants, ſhall have ſuch double coſts, and all other advantages and reme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies, as in and by the ſaid former Act is limited, directed and provided.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:35512:92"/>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
